Leon Chike Nwankwo

leonchike@gmail.com · (240) 676-7727 · Washington, D.C. · linkedin.com/in/chike-nwankwo · leonchike.me

A resilient product manager merging human-centered design with technical expertise. I excel in fostering agile, empathetic teams focused on expansive thinking and winning strategies. Demonstrated success in increasing ROI and product impact through collaborative innovation and a deep commitment to mission alignment, ensuring product and team success.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Product Engineering Manager

2022 - Present

Rebuildee, Inc. (Acquired by RapidSOS)

- Integrated the core inventory, supply chain, and payments API into RapidSOS platform, designing robust infrastructure as part of the Rebuildee acquisition.
- Elevated user experience through a deep understanding and application of humancentered design principles, driving 5x user and 17x API growth within 9 months.
- Achieved 30% reduction in time-to-market and 67% decrease in production bugs via transformative changes in testing, release management, and design strategies.
- Led the successful transition to a microservices architecture and optimized project teams to enhance the growth and reliability of the product.

Manager, Management Consulting

2016 - 2022

Deloitte Consulting / Deloitte Digital, LLC

- Streamlined JP Morgan's processing time by creating a reinforced learning (AI / RPA) application, resulting in an annual savings of 95,000 work hours (\$2.9M).
- Managed 25+ software projects, ensuring they aligned with the organization's mission and achieving a 95% on-time rate with budgets up to \$5M.
- Interviewed, vetted, and hired candidates, expanding the team from 11 to 60 in two years, enhancing client value and service delivery.
- Steered a team of 60 high performers, prioritizing user-centric design, continuous discovery, and cross-functional collaboration to drive iterative product development.
- Fostered a culture of open communication, encouraging problem-solving, boosting creativity, and enhancing client relationships.

Product Manager

2015 - 2016

Capital One Innovation Labs, LLC

- Crafted a data-driven risk-tolerance algorithm, offering Capital One advisors personalized investment strategies.
- Integrated client risk simulation into digital banking experience, resulting in a 65% increase in monthly client interactions and an 87% net promoter score (NPS), strengthening advisor-client connections and client loyalty.

Co-Founder, Software Engineering

2013 - 2015

- Kivvik, Inc.
- Engineered a communication platform for financial advisors, surfacing their client's life updates and evolving risk profiles - redefining client-advisor interactions for deeper personalization.
- Led cross-functional teams to align our product vision with our mission.
 Implemented operational initiatives and formed strategic partnerships to optimize product-market fit and meet industry demands.

SKILLS

Technical

Javascript/Typescript, Python, ReactJS, NextJS, ExpressJS, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AWS, Google Cloud, Git

Product Management

Figma, BigQuery, Jira, Metabase, UX design, agile & scrum, market & competitive analysis, product lifecycle management

Leadership & Communication

Team management, crossfunctional collaboration, stakeholder communication, strategic planning

EDUCATION

Rhetoric

Master of Business Administration

2022

2014

Georgetown University, Washington, D.C.

Bachelor of Science, Finance, Accounting, and

k

University of Maryland, College Park, MD

COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Human-Computer Interaction Graduate 2020

Stanford School of Engineering

Product Manager
Certification (PMC)

2016

Product School

Certificate